# CHRISTY SPARKS

DEVELOPER | SPARKSMOTION.COM



## CONTACT

Montgomery, AL christy@sparksmotion.com (334) 324-0902 Github: @csparx

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science
in Computer Science
Troy University | Alabama

## **AWARDS**

AAMA Impact Award - 2023

Public Relations Council Medallion Award - 2020

Public Relations Council Award of Excellence - 2019

# **SKILLS**

Java MySQL

Spring Boot PostgreSQL

Angular Python

React RESTful APIs

Node. js Wordpress

Javascript Drupal

HTML/CSS AWS

PHP/Laravel Git

# **PROFILE**

Seasoned web developer with over a decade of experience overseeing web projects, crafting impactful web applications, and driving digital growth. I bring a self-driven, team-oriented mindset, coupled with a passion for learning and tackling new challenges.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **WEBMASTER**

Alabama Community College System | Montgomery, AL | 2019 - Present

Responsible for overseeing all aspects of web development, including the creation of internal/exterior web applications, testing, database management, mobile web optimization, API integrations, error resolution, server maintenance, and application upkeep. Coordinates with various sectors within the system and provides best practices for fellow colleges.

#### **WEB CONTENT MANAGER**

Café Racer Magazine | Remote | 2012 - Present

Revamped e-commerce site, boosting sales potential. Contributed to Café Racer Magazine's expansion by launching a digital magazine and Café Racer TV streaming subscription for purchase. Collaborated with sales representative to drive supplementary ad revenue. Edited multiple episodes of Ton-Up TV, a Café Racer Magazine offshoot featuring custom motorcycle content.

#### WEB DEVELOPER

Hatton-Brown Publishers, Inc. | Montgomery, AL | 2007 - 2018

Served as the web developer for Hatton-Brown, a production company that has grown to be the influential leader in forest-based publishing for over 60 years. Managed the website division for over 15 different magazines and expositions. Sole creator and organizer of HB Media, a web development service offered to small business owners.